Eleutelcio Bruno Afonso Fernandes Software Developer

Leeds, West Yorkshire 07587 696 045

brunoaf1523@gmail.com



https://github.com/brunoFernandes21



https://www.linkedin.com/in/bruno-fernandes-879b0725a/

PROFILE

I am a very motivated and positive person and I work hard to achieve my objectives. I am passionate about learning and want to continue building my skills. After my experience at the University of Leeds, I decided to teach myself Web Development so that I could potentially get into the industry. I chose Northcoders because I believed that based on their outstanding reputation and success, they would equip me with all the knowledge and skills I needed to have in order to kick start my career. I love working in a team environment where I can learn from others and contribute to the success of the team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Language: JavaScript

Front End: HTML5, CSS, CSS Frameworks (Bootstrap, Tailwind, Sass), React, Next, Vue **Back End:** Node, Express, Firebase, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, API development, Unit testing

Testing: Jest

Other: Test Driven Development (TDD), Pair Programming, Agile Methodology, Git, Chrome Dev Tools, Web

application deployment, Problem solving

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Project name: Developer Portfolio (Front End)

Tech used: Nextjs, React Icons, Tailwind Css, Css, framer-motion, emailJs

Live Project: https://bruno-dev-portfolio.netlify.app/

Project name: Total Fitness (Full Stack)

Tech used: React, React Icons, Tailwind Css, Css, Axios, Express, MongoDB, Firebase

Live Project: Not available for live preview.

Github repo: https://github.com/brunoFernandes21/Total_Fitness

Project name: Meals App (Front End)

Tech used: React, React Icons, Tailwind Css, Css, Axios

Live Project: https://brunos-meals-app.netlify.app/

Project name: Bruno's Blog

Tech used: React, Redux Toolkit, Tailwind Css, Css, Axios, Fake API

Live project: https://bfblog.netlify.app/

Northcoders Projects

Project name: Northcoders News (Front End)

Tech used: React, Css, Tailwind Css, react icons and Axios for data fetching, Git

Live project: https://www.bfnc-news.com/

Project name: Northcoders News (Back End)

Tech used: Express Js for Server, PostGreSLQ for Database, Jest for testing **Live project:** https://brunofernandes-northcoders-news.onrender.com/api

Project name: Books Buzz (Full stack Group Project)

Tech used: Next Js, Css, Tailwind Css, Firebase, Google Books API.

Live project: https://books-buzz-app.netlify.app/landing-page

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Trainee Developer Northcoders 15/05/2023 - 15/08/2023

Northcoders is a very well known Tech school in the UK that specialises in transforming people's lives by providing excellent coding bootcamps to aspiring Developers. Their coding school offers courses for absolute beginners and junior software developers to help them kick-start and advance their coding careers.

Course: **Software Development Bootcamp** - The course covers a mixture of back-end and front-end with a focus on building web applications. The main objective is to teach the skills students need to become Software Developers.

- Successfully built and deployed an API (Application Programming Interface)
- Applied all the knowledge acquired to create a fully functional Server and Database
- Solidified my knowledge and understanding of JavaScript fundamentals
- Learned a new testing framework named jest for backend testing
- Worked on group project using Agile methodology

Customer Assistant Waitrose and Partners 18/11/2020 - Present

- Provide excellent customer service to our customers
- Stock and replace products to avoid any damages
- Keep shelves fully stocked with fresh products
- Achieve daily tasks by following procedures

Other Relevant Skills

Teamwork, planning, time management, organization, self-motivation, autonomous, video production, photo editing, research, social media, content creation.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

Applied Computer Science University of Leeds 04/09/2016 - 28/06/2018

Key Modules: Professional Computing, Software Engineering, Algorithms, Artificial Intelligence, Databases, Operating Systems, Networks, Mathematics.

Projects:

Sorting algorithms; Web development (Creation of websites and web applications); Binary tree, Creation of a command-line shell, Creation of user interface using C++, Software development (group project).

Programming languages learned: Java; C; C++; Python;

Web Programming: HTML; CSS; Flask.

Systems used: Gitlab, IntelliJ IDEA for Java Development. Linux.